{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Classical","Modern"],"question":"What is the name of the art style that literally means \"rebirth\" in French?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cameroon","incorrectAnswers":["Algeria","Mauritius","Tunisia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Douala?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1974","incorrectAnswers":["1956","1962","1968"],"question":"In which year was GPS invented?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Girl, You'll Be a Woman Soon","incorrectAnswers":["Twist and Shout","Landslide","American Woman"],"question":"Which song was originally recorded by Neil Diamond and was later covered by Urge Overkill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","Qatar","Iran"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Kuwait?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A Clockwork Orange","incorrectAnswers":["The Public Enemy","The Adventures of Robin Hood","Rain Man"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Alex DeLarge'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Methane","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium nitrate","Iron Oxide","Calcium sulphate dihydrate"],"question":"What chemical has the formula CH4?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A determined Cuban immigrant takes over a drug cartel.","incorrectAnswers":["A man refuses assistance as he ages and begins to his own mind.","A Polish Jew struggles to survive the destruction of the Warsaw ghetto of World War II.","A cafe owner decides whether or not to help his ex and her husband escape the Nazis in French Morocco."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Scarface?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"13.8 billion years","incorrectAnswers":["13.8 quadrillion years","13.8 million years","13.8 thousand years"],"question":"What is the approximate age of the universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dermatologist","incorrectAnswers":["Permologist","Skin Clinician","Visologist"],"question":"What is a skin specialist called?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Belgium","Norway"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Barcelona?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Butterflies","incorrectAnswers":["Bears","Seals","Penguins"],"question":"Admiral and Monarch belong to which group of animals?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grand Marnier","incorrectAnswers":["Disaronno","Limoncello","Midori"],"question":"Which of these is an orange flavoured liqueur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"We Don't Have to Take Our Clothes Off","incorrectAnswers":["I'Ve Never Been to Me","Pop Muzik","Unbelievable"],"question":"Jermaine Stewart had a one hit wonder in 1986 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Swimming","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Rowing","Track and field"],"question":"With which sport is Mark Spitz associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'Bad Romance'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["China","New Zealand","South Korea"],"question":"In which country is the city of Nagoya?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Nikon","incorrectAnswers":["Olympus","Kodak","Canon"],"question":"Which photography brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'At the heart of the image'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Aldous Huxley","Ray Bradbury","Philip K. Dick"],"question":"Who wrote the famous dystopian novel which features the quote 'Big Brother is watching you'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"West","incorrectAnswers":["North","East","South"],"question":"What is the meaning of 'Maghrib' in Arabic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Women","incorrectAnswers":["Buddenbrooks","David Copperfield","Jane Eyre"],"question":"In which book does 'Aunt March' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Kit","incorrectAnswers":["An Owlet","A Caterpillar","A Tadpole"],"question":"What would you call a baby skunk?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cinco de Mayo","incorrectAnswers":["Día de la Independencia","Día de los Muertos","Día de la Revolución"],"question":"What is the name of the Mexican national holiday which celebrates Mexico's victory over France at the Battle of Puebla?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A drove","incorrectAnswers":["A covey","A murder","A sloth"],"question":"What is the word for a group of cattle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Miracles","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rhythm and blues vocal group released the song 'You've Really Got a Hold on Me'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Falco","incorrectAnswers":["Jermaine Stewart","Vanilla Ice","Sir Mix-A-Lot"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1984 with Rock Me Amedeus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Smiths","Roxy Music","Led Zeppelin"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'From Me to You'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A host","incorrectAnswers":["A run","A field","A charm"],"question":"What is the word for a group of sparrows?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Central America","incorrectAnswers":["India","Central Asia","Europe"],"question":"Where in the world are green beans originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Jamaica","incorrectAnswers":["Cuba","Mexico","Brazil"],"question":"Where did jerk chicken originate?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Billie Eilish","incorrectAnswers":["A-ha","Gladys Knight","Chris Cornell"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film No Time To Die?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Horse and His Boy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Liver","incorrectAnswers":["Kidney","Stomach","Bladder"],"question":"What does hepatitis affect?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Frank Capra","incorrectAnswers":["Orson Welles","John Ford","Howard Hawks"],"question":"Who directed the 1946 classic 'It's A Wonderful Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Teddy Roosevelt","incorrectAnswers":["Abraham Lincoln","George Washington","Donald Trump"],"question":"Which US president was once the police commissioner of New York City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Shakira ","incorrectAnswers":["Enrique Iglesias","Pitbull","Jennifer Lopez"],"question":"Who released the album 'Pies Descalzos'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bolivia","incorrectAnswers":["Pakistan","Morocco","Uganda"],"question":"Quechua is a language spoken in which of these countries?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Brunei is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1991","incorrectAnswers":["1987","1995","1999"],"question":"Terminator 2: Judgment Day was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Voltaire","incorrectAnswers":["Stendhal","Paulo Coelho","Isabel Allende"],"question":"Which author wrote 'L'Ingénu'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Avril Lavigne","incorrectAnswers":["Alanis Morissette","Neil Young","Joni Mitchell"],"question":"Which Canadian singer released the song 'Girlfriend'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Muse","incorrectAnswers":["Tears for Fears","Bullet For My Valentine","Enter Shikari"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Sunburn'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robert Zemeckis","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Forrest Gump?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Mariah Carey","incorrectAnswers":["Rihanna","Beyonce","Christina Aguilera"],"question":"Which Singing Diva Flopped At The Box Office With Her Debut Movie “Glitter”?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Flambé","incorrectAnswers":["Sauté","Al denté","Brulée"],"question":"What French verb, involving liquor and a match, is the last step in preparing Steak Diane?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Hobbit","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","Bluebeard"],"question":"In which book does 'Bilbo Baggins' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vulpine","incorrectAnswers":["Feline","Canine","Serpentine"],"question":"What adjective describes a fox?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Vancouver Whitecaps","incorrectAnswers":["Vancouver FC","Vancouver 76ers","Vancouver Nuggets"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in Vancouver?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Physicist","incorrectAnswers":["Physician","Physiatrist","Physicalist"],"question":"What term is used for someone who studies physics?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Riyadh","incorrectAnswers":["Mecca","Medina","Jeddah"],"question":"What is the capital of Saudi Arabia","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice ","incorrectAnswers":["Grape","Wheat","Plum"],"question":"What is the Japanese Drink 'Sake' Made From?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Monty Python and the Holy Grail","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Star Wars","The Wizard of Oz"],"question":"From which 1975 film classic does the quote 'Your mother was a hamster and your father smelt of elderberries' come?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Charles Lindbergh","incorrectAnswers":["Orson Welles","Albert Einstein","Mark Twain"],"question":"Which famous person's infant child was kidnapped in 1932?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire","incorrectAnswers":["The Sea of Monsters","Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea","The Mysterious Island"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'The villagers of Little Hangleton still called it \"the Riddle House\" even though it has been many years since the Riddle family had lived there.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"What we've got here is failure to communicate.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bond. James Bond.\"","\"That’s a bingo!\"","\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Cool Hand Luke'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Orchid","incorrectAnswers":["Lily","Cactus","Nightshade"],"question":"Which type of plant does vanilla come from? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mach Number","incorrectAnswers":["Speed Ratio Number","Sound Multiple","Chain Number"],"question":"What is the name of the number that represents how fast something is travelling relative to the speed of sound?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tajikistan","incorrectAnswers":["Azerbaijan","Georgia","Pakistan"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Dushanbe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Carpathia","incorrectAnswers":["Lusitania","Iberia","Olympia"],"question":"What was the first ship to reach the Titanic after it sank?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"8","incorrectAnswers":["6","10","14"],"question":"How many limbs does an octopus have?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Alice in Chains","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American grunge band released the studio album 'The Devil Put Dinosaurs Here'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sei","incorrectAnswers":["Zes","Seis","Dieci"],"question":"What is the Italian word for 'six'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dr. Crane","incorrectAnswers":["Dr. House","Dr. Strange","Dr. Dolittle"],"question":"What is the name of the radio presenter, played by Kelsey Grammer, on the TV show 'Frasier'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gene Roddenberry","incorrectAnswers":["George Lucas","Linus Torvalds","Stanley Kubrick"],"question":"Who was the creator of Star Trek?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Abstract expressionism","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Northern Renaissance","Fauvism"],"question":"The painting \"No. 5, 1948\" by Jackson Pollock is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Shrew","incorrectAnswers":["Rat","Squirrel","Beaver"],"question":"Which Rodent Has Given It's Name To A Mean Spirited Or Bad Tempered Woman?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gladiator","incorrectAnswers":["Mr. Smith Goes to Washington","Schindler's List","Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A former Roman General seeks revenge against the emperor who murdered his family.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Hoban","incorrectAnswers":["Frank Lloyd Wright","Christopher Wren","Otto Wagner"],"question":"Which architect designed The Whitehouse?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Young MC","incorrectAnswers":["Blind Melon","The Weather Girls","Faith No More"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1989 with Bust a Move?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Microsoft","incorrectAnswers":["Apple","Amazon","Google"],"question":"Which tech company was founded in 1981 and is based in Redmond, Washington?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Sympathy for the Devil\" by the Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"Crazy Train\" by Ozzy Osbourne","\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Please allow me to introduce myself / I'm a man of wealth and taste / I've been around for a long, long year / Stole many a man's soul and faith...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"St. Stephen","incorrectAnswers":["St. Marko","St. Cyril","St. Alexander"],"question":"Who was the first king of Hungary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Jordan","incorrectAnswers":["Malta","Peru","Saudi Arabia"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Petra?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Caesarion","incorrectAnswers":["Octavian","Augustus","Commodus"],"question":"What was the name of the son of Cleopatra & Julius Caesar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bibble","incorrectAnswers":["Valetudinarian","Winklepicker","Donkey Engine"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'to drink often; to eat and/or drink noisily'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Socrates","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Jean-Paul Sartre","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A Spider","incorrectAnswers":["A Pig","A Sheep","A Horse"],"question":"In E.B. White's classic children's book \"Charlotte's Web\", what kind of animal is Charlotte?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lobster","incorrectAnswers":["Egg","Ham","Tomato"],"question":"What type of food can be prepared 'Newberg style'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A sord","incorrectAnswers":["A parliament","A paddling","A skulk"],"question":"What is the word for a group of mallards?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Stratego","incorrectAnswers":["Chess","Connect Four","Life"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must move pieces around a board in an effort to capture their opponent's flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Last Battle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"McDonald's","incorrectAnswers":["Apple","Abercrombie & Fitch","Starbuck's"],"question":"What Hugely Successful Chain Of Stores First Opened Its Doors In 1954 In California?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Prostitute","incorrectAnswers":["Delicious","Garden","Mountain"],"question":"What does the 'Puttanesca' in 'Pasta Puttanesca' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Larva","incorrectAnswers":["A Bunny","A Kitten","A Calf"],"question":"What would you call a baby wasp?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Hawaii","Alaska","Vermont"],"question":"What US state is nicknamed the Golden State?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Edgar Allan Poe","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Nathaniel Hawthorne","Mario Puzo"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Oval Portrait'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United Arab Emirates","incorrectAnswers":["Qatar","Kuwait","Lebanon"],"question":"In which country is the city of Ajman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"a foot","incorrectAnswers":["a hand","an ear","a nose"],"question":"What body part are you said to have 'in the door' if you're lucky, and 'in the grave' if you're not?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Amaretto","incorrectAnswers":["Grappa","Limoncello","Schnapps"],"question":"What drink is an almond liqueur that comes from the Italian word for 'bitter'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Attila","incorrectAnswers":["Leonidas","Ariston","Anaxander"],"question":"Which of these people was a leader of the Hunnic empire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ursula K. Le Guin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","George R. R. Martin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Left Hand of Darkness'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"General Motors","incorrectAnswers":["Ford","Toyota","Daimler"],"question":"What company owns the brand 'Chevrolet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Woodstock Festival","incorrectAnswers":["The first nuclear bomb test","The Watergate scandal","The assassination of Martin Luther King Jr"],"question":"What Happened At Max Yasgur's Dairy Farm In New York State in 1969?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Simone Biles","incorrectAnswers":["Aly Raisman","Gabby Douglas","Mary Lou Retton"],"question":"Which American gymnast won the vault at every U.S. Championship she competed in from 2014 to 2021, a total of six times?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nightwish","incorrectAnswers":["Haloo Helsinki!","Hanoi Rocks","Children of Bodom"],"question":"Which Finnish symphonic metal band released the album 'Dark Passion Play'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vietnam","incorrectAnswers":["Malaysia","Singapore","Brunei"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Cambodia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Harare","incorrectAnswers":["Monrovia","Baku","Bulawayo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Zimbabwe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Egypt","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Peru","Mexico"],"question":"In which country would you find the Pyramids of Giza?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gasoline Alley","incorrectAnswers":["Drug Alley","Happy Alley","Dead Alley"],"question":"Rod Stewart's first album was named after which alley?","difficulty":"hard"},